<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: perlbrew | Smonff Shurfs]]></title>
  <link href="http://smonff.github.io/blog/categories/perlbrew/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://smonff.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-23T18:45:04+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://smonff.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Smonff]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[smonff@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Perlbrew on Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://smonff.github.io/blog/2014/03/23/using-perlbrew-on-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-23T13:33:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://smonff.github.io/blog/2014/03/23/using-perlbrew-on-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I discovered that I was using <a href="https://metacpan.org/pod/release/FLORA/perl-5.14.2/pod/perl.pod">Perl 5, version 14.2</a> from the Ubuntu 12.04 packages (v5.14.2). It includes 57 registered patches. As it is a 2011 version, I've decided to switch from the Ubuntu packages that to a more recent one (and considered as stable by the Perl community).</p>

<p>As I love to use <code>local::lib</code> and <code>cpanm</code>, a possible way to install this 5.18.2 last stable version, I've choosed to use <a href="http://perlbrew.pl/"><code>Perlbrew</code></a> to achieve this. The tool seems as convenient as <code>cpanm</code> and <code>local::lib</code>.</p>

<p><code>Perlbrew</code> is :</p>

<ul>
<li><em>a tool to install different verisons of perls</em></li>
<li><em>an admin-free installation management</em> system, means, as for local::lib, you don't even need to have sudo rights to use it, so you don't have to suck the admin's ass</li>
<li>just like <code>RVM</code> for those who knows Ruby</li>
</ul>


<p>The reason I write this post is that I encountered a tiny problem when installing <code>Perlbrew</code> on an Ubuntu box, so I hope it could be useful for you.</p>

<p>I assume that you already have <code>cpanm</code> and <code>local::lib</code> installed (no <code>root</code>).</p>

<p>We install <code>Perlbrew</code> :</p>

<pre><code>$ cpanm perlbrew
</code></pre>

<p>Then, we initialize it's environment. Don't forget this part or it won't work :</p>

<pre><code>$ perlbrew init

perlbrew root (~/perl5/perlbrew) is initialized.

Append the following piece of code to the end of your ~/.bash_profile and start a
new shell, perlbrew should be up and fully functional from there:

    source ~/perl5/perlbrew/etc/bashrc

Simply run `perlbrew` for usage details.

Happy brewing!
</code></pre>

<p>It create some files in <code>~/.perlbrew</code>. You need to add the one that fit your environment in your configuration file (<code>.bashrc</code> or other) :</p>

<pre><code># In .bashrc
source ~/perl5/perlbrew/etc/bashrc
</code></pre>

<p>Now start a new shell or <code>source</code> your configuration file, that's it ! You can check wich Perls are available :</p>

<pre><code>$ perlbrew available
  perl-5.19.10
  perl-5.18.2
  perl-5.16.3
  perl-5.14.4
  perl-5.12.5
  perl-5.10.1
  perl-5.8.9
  perl-5.6.2
  perl5.005_04
  perl5.004_05
  perl5.003_07
</code></pre>

<p>So pick a version, or ask for the last <em>stable</em>. In fact, that's the moment I encountered an issue with <code>Perlbrew</code> and <code>Devel::PatchPerl.pm</code>. I asked for the installation of last stable Perl but it failed :</p>

<pre><code>$ perlbrew install stable
Installing /home/smonff/perl5/perlbrew/build/perl-5.18.2 into
~/perl5/perlbrew/perls/perl-5.18.2

This could take a while. You can run the following command on
another shell to track the status:

  tail -f ~/perl5/perlbrew/build.perl-5.18.2.log

Installation process failed. To spot any issues, check

  /home/smonff/perl5/perlbrew/build.perl-5.18.2.log

If some perl tests failed and you still want install this
distribution anyway, do:

  (cd /home/smonff/perl5/perlbrew/build/perl-5.18.2; make install)

You might also want to try upgrading patchperl before trying again:

  perlbrew install-patchperl

Generally, if you need to install a perl distribution known to
have minor test failures, do one of these command to avoid seeing this message

  perlbrew --notest install stable
  perlbrew --force install stable
</code></pre>

<p>As the process was failing, I've tailed the logs :</p>

<pre><code>tail -f ~/perl5/perlbrew/build.perl-5.18.2.log
Can't locate Devel/PatchPerl.pm in @INC (@INC contains: /etc/perl 
/usr/local/lib/perl/5.14.2 /usr/local/share/perl/5.14.2
/usr/lib/perl5 /usr/share/perl5 /usr/lib/perl/5.14 
/usr/share/perl/5.14 /usr/local/lib/site_perl .) at 
/home/smonff/perl5/bin/patchperl line 12.
BEGIN failed--compilation aborted at /home/smonff/perl5/bin/patchperl line 12.
</code></pre>

<p>Finally, I found the answer on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/16113467/perlbrew-fails-with-cant-locate-devel-patchperl-pm">StackOverflow</a>, even if it was clearly mentioned in the <code>Perlbrew</code> logs, you should better read sentences to the end :</p>

<pre><code>$ perlbrew install-patchperl  
</code></pre>

<p>I've tryied to update a <code>Devel::PatchPerl</code> before but updating stupidely without understanding or before reading the doc is useless.Perlbrew seems to embark it's own <code>Devel::PatchPerl</code> in <code>~/perl5/perlbrew/bin</code>, that's why it conflicts with the core version.</p>

<p>Now you got this enviroment ready, you can install Perl very very easily :</p>

<pre><code>$ perlbrew install stable 
perl-5.18.2 is successfully installed.
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
